大家动作快点  4小时后的航班
You guys, hurry up. The flight leaves in four hours.
打的还要时间  路上可能会堵车  飞机还可能提前起飞
It could take time to get a taxi! There could be traffic! The plane could leave early.
到了伦敦  入境通关还要排队   快点
When we get to London, there could be a line at customs. Come on.
6小时的飞机  够她念了
Six-hour trip to London. That's a lot of Monica.
护照  打勾  相机  打勾  旅行支票  打勾
Passport, check. Camera, check. Traveler's checks, check.
你在叫谁 "打勾"   我自己
Who are you saying "check" to? Myself.
记起一样就打一个勾
For remembering to pack the thing.
做好一件事  就打个勾勾
You know, you do a good thing, you get a check.
这是我妈的习惯   我从不觉得很怪啊
My mom does it. I never realized it was weird.
我妈都把头塞进烤箱里
Hey, my mom used to put her head in the oven, so...
其实只有一次  但觉得蛮怪异的
Actually, she only did it the one time. But it was pretty weird.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿  准备好了吗
Hey. Are you ready yet?
好了  机票带了吗  在这里  打勾
Yep. You got the tickets? Oh, got them right here. Check.
去伦敦喽   宝贝  走吧
It's all London, baby. Here we go.
护照呢
You got your passport?
衣橱第三个抽屉里   弄丢就糟了
Yeah, in my third drawer of my dresser. You don't wanna lose that.
快去
Oh. There it is.
老友记  第四季  第23集  罗斯的婚礼（上）
Friends  S04E23  The One With Ross's Wedding Parts I
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
如果要用吸尘器  就在我柜子里的左手边
Okay, if you need the vacuum, it's in my closet on the left side.
垃圾袋在冰箱旁边
The garbage bags are next to the refrigerator.
瑞秋会在  我不能问她吗
But Rachel's gonna be here too. Can't I just ask her?
哦  行啊  回头你试试
Heh. Yeah, okay. Give that a try.
好啦好啦  快走吧
All right, let's do it. Woohoo.
伦敦  宝贝
Yeah. Cheerio. London, baby.
我绝对不会烦  伦敦  宝贝
Because that's not gonna get annoying. London, baby!
你知道吗  我错了
Oh, you know what? I was wrong. Ha, ha.
行  人都到了  我们该走了
Well, we're all here. I guess we should get going.
我真想过去拥抱你一下
Oh, I wanna come over there and give you a hug...
祝你婚礼一切顺利  但是我起不来
...and wish you luck on your wedding, but I can't get up.
我过来拥抱你好了  太好了  能不能帮我把报纸带过来
Oh, I'll come hug you. Great, can you bring me the newspaper?
好啊
Yeah.
快快乐乐的结婚吧   谢谢
Have a great wedding. Oh. Thanks.
钱德  我也想抱你  嘿
Hey, Chandler, I wanna hug you too. Hey.
顺便去你家餐台  把我的书拿来
And you might as well bring me my book. It's on the counter in your apartment.
我们要走了  玩得开心点
So we're off. Have fun.
谢谢
Thanks. Oh.
你居然不能去
Oh. I can't believe you're not gonna be there.
是啊
Oh, I know.
去嘛  你为什么不能去  什么
So come. Why don't you come? What?
去伦敦  一起去  拜托  我会很高兴
To London. Come to London. Please? It would mean so much to me.
我要忙  对不起
Yeah, well, I gotta work. I'm sorry.
为什么不能请两天假  我不行  我说过了
Why can't you take a couple of days off? Because I can't. I told you. No, I can't.
这是我的婚礼
This is my wedding.
真的来不及了  走走走
All right, you know what? Now we are late. Let's go, let's go, let's go!
好吧  回来再让你看录影带
Fine, you'll watch it on video when we get back.
菲比  你的书书  苏苏
Here you go, Phoebe. Here you go, Phoebo, Phoobala, Phobayboo.
你啊
You. Ha, ha.
走吧   菲比再见
All right, let's go. Bye, Pheebs.
再见  菲比  再见
Bye. Bye, Pheebs.
再见
Mwah. Goodbye. Mwah.
再见  旅途愉快
Bye. Safe flight.
伦敦  宝贝
London, baby.
天哪  你要抱抱吗
Oh, God. Oh. Do you need a hug?
你不必拿东西给我
You don't have to bring me anything.
（伦敦  马力欧饭店）
钱德   做点动作
All right, Chandler, do something.
来啊  做动作啊  我在做啊  我正在当你不存在
Come on, do something. I am. I'm ignoring you.
好吧  你来拍我吧  好
Okay, I'm gonna be the on-camera guy. All right.
第一站   西敏寺
First stop, Westminster Abbey.
那是什么  伦敦啊  宝贝
Oh, what the hell is that? That's London, baby.
好  饭店在这里
All right, the hotel's here.
等一下  不对  我们要去…
Wait. No, we wanna go...
不对
No.
我知道了
I know.
我得站到地图上去
I'm gonna have to go into the map.
要是里面有个小钱德  踩死他
Okay, if you see a little version of me in there, kill it.
我知道了
I got it.
走吧
Here we go.
听着  我们不是要这样逛大街吧
Okay, listen, listen, we're not gonna have to walk this way the entire time, are we?
你害的我又乱了
Oh, man, you made me lose it.
那时候还不到10点
…and that was all before 10 o'clock.
厨师告诉我说用基辅鸡肉代替龙嵩叶鸡肉
The caterer rang and said it was going to be Chicken Kiev instead of Chicken Tarragon.
然后花店又说没有郁金香了
The florist phoned to say there aren't any tulips.
然后大提琴手得了  腕关节综合症
Oh, and then the cellist has carpal tunnel syndrome...
喔 喔 喔   艾蜜莉  亲爱的  好吗
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Emily, honey. Okay?
好吧  我也去你妈的  什么
Well, up yours too. What?
不  这是暂停的意思  对不起
No, no. That's "time-out." Sorry.
放轻松   一切都会很美好
Sweetie, you gotta relax. Everything's gonna be great, okay?
走吧  走吧
Come on, come on.
基辅鸡
Chicken kiev? Mm-hm.
听起来最后这道菜很美味吧
Doesn't that sound delicious at the last minute?
是啊  但鲑鱼一类的东西
I know, but something like salmon would just...
比鸡肉看起来档次更高一点
It would be so much more elegant than chicken.
而且你还不用担心会感染沙门氏菌
And you wouldn't have to worry about the salmonella.
真想赶快看到婚礼场地
So, I can't wait to see where you're getting married.
是啊  没错  那里很美  她父母就在那里结婚
Yeah. Yeah. Yes, This place is beautiful. Emily's parents got married here.
还是不敢相信  它居然要被拆了
So, can't believe they're tearing it down.
你绝对没看过那么美的房子
It really is the most lovely building you'll ever see.
就在…
I mean, it's over...
天哪
Oh, my God.
还不错
It's nice.
我的天哪
Oh. Oh, my God.
怎么会这样  我们怎么办
How can this be happening? What are we gonna do?
放心  不会有问题的
It's all right! Everything's gonna be all right.
怎么会没问题  说得也是
How is it gonna be all right? Uh-huh, I see that.
我跟拿铲子的那个人聊过了  知道怎么回事了
Okay, I talked to the guy with the shovel and I found out what happened.
怎么回事  提前了几天拆除
What? What? They tore it down a few days early.
漂亮
All right.
西敏寺
Westminster Abbey.
绝对是我见过最美的寺
Hands down, best abbey I ever seen.
嘿
Hey.
好
Okay.
钱德   你觉得西敏寺如何
What do you think of the abbey, Chandler?
很宏伟   他们正打算改名
Oh, I think it's great. It's great. Y'know, They're thinking of changing the name of this place.
真的  改成什么  改成 "摄像机收起来"
Really? To what? To "Put the Camera Away."
老兄  你可以改叫 "西敏寺神经病"了
Man, you are Westminster Crabby.
别起来  你需要什么  没什么
Honey, don't get up. What do you need? Oh, no. Oh, nothing.
没关系  我就是留下来照顾你的  需要什么  什么都行
Come on. I'm here to take care of you. What do you need? Anything.
好吧  屁股夹到内裤了
Okay, I have a wedgie.
那你还是自己解决
Okay, that is all you.
中午想吃什么
So, what do you want for lunch?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
我们是得吃饭  是啊  我得吃啊
I guess we have to eat. Yeah, I do.
怎么了
What's the matter?
我应付罗斯的方式真差劲啊
I'm just bummed the way I left things with Ross.
真后悔骗他说我要上班的
I wish I didn't lie to him about having to work.
他好像很气我
He seemed so mad at me.
别太责备自己  要是我还爱的人要结婚
Ah, don't be so hard on yourself. If someone I was still in love with was...
还爱的人  是啊
Still in love with? Yeah.
我才没有爱着罗斯呢
I'm not in love with Ross.
是没有  那很好
No, no. Good.
我也没有
Yeah, me neither.
菲比  我不去是因为他是我的旧情人
Phoebe, I'm not going to Ross' wedding, because he's my ex-boyfriend...
去了会很不自在
...and that would be really uncomfortable.
不是因为我还爱着他  我跟大家一样喜欢罗斯
Not because I'm still in love with him. Hey, I like Ross as much as the next guy.
我对他的确有感情  但那不是爱
You know, clearly I have feelings for him, but feelings don't mean love.
我对罗斯还有爱的感觉吗
You know, I mean, do I still have loving feelings for Ross?
有
Yeah.
我一直都有
I have continuing feelings of love.
但那并不表示我还爱着他
But that doesn't mean that I'm still in love with him.
我对他还有性趣  但我当然爱他
You know, I mean, I have sexual feelings for him, but I do love him.
天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my...
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
我们以为你知道  我们
We thought you knew. We?
对  我们都知道  还经常在聊
Yeah, we all know. We talk about it all the time.
你们都知道  罗斯知道吗
You all know? Does Ross know?
不  罗斯什么都不知道
Oh, no. Ross doesn't know anything.
你们居然没告诉我
Oh. I cannot believe you didn't tell me.
我们以为你知道  那么明显
Because we thought you knew. It's so obvious.
告诉你等于告诉摩妮卡
God, it would be like, you know, telling Monica:
"喂  你很爱干净喔"
"Hey," you know, "you like things clean."
你好
Hi.
先生想买什么
So, what are you fine gentlemen in the market for?
有围巾  明信片  你看
We've got scarves, souvenir postcards. Check this out, huh?
棒及了
Oh, yeah.
这个就对了  你觉得呢
That's the stuff. What do you think?
我不必买印着  "与笨蛋同行" 的T恤了
Well, I'm not gonna have to buy that "I'm with stupid" T-shirt anymore.
我喜欢  钱给你
Well, I like it. Here you go.
你不是来真的吧  你丢我的脸丢得还不够吗
All right, look, you're not really gonna buy that are you? Don't you think you've embarrassed me enough for one day?
我丢你的脸
Oh, I embarrass you?
我假装不认识你  无法回答
How can I answer that when I'm pretending I don't know you?
他是在嫉妒  伦敦人都在戴
He's just jealous. You'll fit right in. All Londoners wear them.
是吗  那这里怎么没人戴
Oh, really? Then how come no one here anywhere is wearing one?
他们都是观光客
They're all tourists.
那好吧  如果你要当街戴着那顶帽子
All right, look, if you insist on wearing that in public, you know...
下午你就自己去逛着玩吧
...you're gonna spend the rest of the afternoon all by yourself.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
如果要在你和帽子之间做选择  我选择帽子
If you're gonna make me choose between you and the hat, I choose the hat.
够英明  谢了
Good choice. Thanks.
好吧  够了  就这样
Okay, look. All right, that's it, okay?
我要走了  我不想再丢脸了
I'm out of here. I'm not gonna be embarrassed anymore.
哈罗  嘿
Hello? Hey.
我跟你爸谈过  你猜怎么
I just spoke to your dad, and you know what?
他觉得可以另外找到场地
He seems to think we'll be able to find a new place for the wedding
不必了  难道  你找到地方了
We don't have to. What, you found a place?
没有  但摩妮卡和我讨论过
No, but Monica and I were talking...
礼堂被拆  我的确很烦
...and I was so upset about the hall being knocked down...
结果她建议  把婚期延后
...and she suggested that we just put the wedding off for a bit.
她说什么  她说如果我不喜欢
She said what? She said if I'm not happy...
临时找个地方  我们就应该延期
...getting married somewhere we can find in a day, well, we should just postpone it.
延期
Postpone it? Heh.
艾蜜莉  你觉得摩妮卡知道  我们爸妈花了多少钱吗
Emily, do you think Monica realizes how much our parents spent on this wedding?
你觉得我妹的那个小脑袋能够理解
Huh? Do you think my sister's teeny, tiny little brain comprehends...
大家特地腾出时间
...that people took time out of their lives...
大老远飞来这里吗
...to fly thousands of miles to be here? Huh?
这么做不对的
This isn't right.
我知道  大家会失望
I realize that people are going to be disappointed.
我相信等我们一切就绪了  他们还是会回来的
I'm sure they'll come back when we can do it right.
我不能叫人家这么做  你会吗
Well, I can't ask people to do that. Would you ask people to do that?
别拿你的裤子指着我
Don't you point your pants at me.
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
像样一点的场地一定没空档
Anywhere that's half-decent will have been booked months ago.
你不懂吗  罗斯  这是我们的婚礼
Ross, don't you understand? This is our wedding I'm talking about.
我只知道延期是不可能的
The only thing I understand is postponing it is not an option.
要结就现在结
This is when we're getting married.
你的意思是  要么就不结了  不  我是说现在就结
What are you saying, it's now or never? No, I'm saying it's now.
否则呢   我没说 "否则"
Or? There's no "or" in mine.
这条裤子是怎么搞的
What is wrong with these pants?
不是裤子的问题  是你自己穿反了
It's not the pants. It's you who's backwards.
要是你不懂这件事对我有多重要
And if, and if you don't understand how important this is to me...
或许  我们就根本不该结婚
well then, perhaps we shouldn't be getting married at all.
艾蜜莉  等一下  别走
Emily, no. Wait, stop. Emily, please...
嘿  嗨
Hey. Hi.
血拼完有没有舒服一点嘛
So did shopping help you feel any better about Ross?
舒服的话曼哈顿的店都不够
Manhattan does not have enough stores.
我能帮你忘了他
Well, I think I can help you get over him.
真的  对
You can? Yeah.
拿几张罗斯的照片
I just need you to bring me some photos of Ross...
一小片巧克力
...and, um, a small piece of chocolate...
和一杯温水来
...and a glass of tepid water.
是不是要跟墓地的土装在一起
Ooh. Is this one of those things where you throw stuff in a bag with graveyard dirt...
挂在面北的树上
...and hang it from a north-facing tree?
要是你也在打嗝的话
Uh, only if you have the hiccups too.
照片是给你的  其它的是我要的
The pictures are for you. The chocolate and water's for me.
我只是不想起来
I just didn't feel like getting up.
我给你看一张罗斯的照片  好
Okay. I'm gonna show you a picture of Ross, okay...
你要去想他不好的地方
...and you're going to remember all the bad things about him, all right?
专心想他的缺点  没问题
Really focus on his flaws. I can do that.
原来交往的时候我就这样
Certainly did that while we were going out. Heh.
好
Okay. Mm.
首先我想先声明  我爱罗斯
Before we get started, I just wanna say, for the record, I love Ross.
他真的好棒
I think he's such a great guy.
好  闭上眼睛
Okay. Now close your eyes.
想像你跟罗斯在一起
And imagine that you're with Ross. Mm-hm.
想像你在亲他
Okay, and imagine that you're kissing him. Mm-hm.
你的手在他的身上游移
You're running your hands all over his body.
你的手抚弄他的头发
And then you run your hands through his hair...
但是好恶心  是某种油
...but, oh, ew, gross, it's some kind of grease, it's... Ugh.
我不知道
I don't know.
他的头发没那么困扰我
I don't know, his hair never bothered me that much.
那应该算是硬而不是油
And you know, it was always more crunchy than it was greasy.
好吧  难度比我想的还高
Okay. This is gonna be harder than I thought.
试试厌恶疗法好了
Um, ahem. Let's try some aversion therapy.
好  好吧  怎么样  好
Okay. All right. Okay? All right.
看着照片  好
Look at the picture. Okay.
好  然后
All right, and, um...
现在觉得怎样  我开始不喜欢你了
Okay. How do you feel now? Well, I like you less.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
抱歉  我才该抱歉
Oh. Sorry. No, no, you know what? I'm sorry.
我不该说你丢我的脸
I really shouldn't have said you that were embarrassing me.
那样很过份
That really wasn't cool.
如果能让你高兴一点   不过我今天过得可没意思了
And if it makes you feel any better, I've had a really lousy day.
我也是
Me too.
真的  当然不是
Yeah? No!
这是我最兴奋的一天
I had the best day ever.
伙计  看看这个
Dude, check this out.
告诉我朋友  你喜欢我的帽子
Say hi to my friend and tell him you like my hat.
好  你朋友叫什么  钱德
Okay, so, what's your friend's name? Oh. Chandler.
钱德  你好
Hi, Chandler.
那不是…
That's... That's...
天啊  那是佛姬  宝贝
Oh, my God. That's Fergie, baby!
乔伊说你不喜欢他的帽子  但我觉得挺时髦的
Joey says you don't really like his hat, but I think it's kind of dashing.
你怎么会  什么时候
When did you...? How...?
我那时正在想办法去白金汉宫
I was trying to figure out how to get to Buckingham Palace, right?
我站到了地图上   然后
So I'm in my map and...
嘿
Hey.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
听说你和艾蜜莉谈过
I understand you had a little talk with Emily.
没错  谈过
Ha, ha. Yes, I did.
不客气
And you are welcome.
是吗
Am I?
是你提议把婚期延后的
And was it your idea to postpone the wedding?
我要上厕所  等我
I'm gonna go to the bathroom. Wait up.
既然你这么会解决问题  问题来了
Hey, hey, since you're the fix-it lady, here's a pickle:
当新娘说她不想结婚时  你怎么办
What do you do when the bride says she doesn't wanna have the wedding at all?
她这么说  对
She said that? Yeah.
为什么  我不知道
Why? I don't know.
我说为了礼堂被拆就延期  实在太蠢了
I told her it was stupid to put off the wedding just because the hall was gone...
然后  她就发火了
...and she, like, flipped out.
天哪   你比我还笨
Oh, my God. You're even dumber than I am.
什么
Excuse me?
你筹备这次婚礼多久了
Ross, how long have you been planning this wedding?
记不清了  1个月吧
I don't know. A month?
艾蜜莉可能从5岁就在计划了
Emily has probably been planning it since she was 5.
从她第一次把枕头套  戴在头上开始
Ever since the first time she took a pillowcase and hung it off her head.
女生都这样
That's what we did.
我们梦想在一个完美的场地
We dreamed about the perfect wedding.
办一场完美的婚礼
In the perfect place.
有一个完美的四层结婚蛋糕
With the perfect four-tiered wedding cake.
上面有木偶小人
With the little people on top.
但最重要的是…
But the most important part...
有个完美的男人
...is that we had the perfect guy...
能理解这一切  对我们有多重要
...who understood just how important all that other stuff was.
这我都不知道
I had no idea.
我以为你披枕头套  是在学 "飞天修女"
That pillowcase thing, I thought you guys were just doing The Flying Nun.
有时候是这样的啦
Sometimes we were.
别哭了
Come on.
帮我想想办法
You gotta help me figure out what to do.
好吗   好
Okay? All right.
走吧
Come on.
刚才的气氛可真紧张  是啊
Whoa. Pretty intense, huh? Yeah.
希望罗斯不会以为  我们是怕尴尬才进厕所
Hey, I hope Ross didn't think that we just went in there because we were uncomfortable being out here!
希望他就是这么想的
I hope he did.
喂   菲比  我是乔伊
Hello? Hey, Pheebs, it's Joey.
乔伊   嘿
Hey, Joey. Hey. Ooh, ooh.
我在地铁看到一个很像你的人
I just saw someone that looks just like you on the subway.
我正想打招呼  又想到他不会在乎他长得像你
I was gonna go over and say hi, but then I figured he doesn't care he looks like you.
你说这些花了我4块钱了
That just cost me 4 bucks.
我打来问问小鸡小鸭好不好
I just called to see how the chick and the duck are doing.
他们跟菲比阿姨玩得很开心
They're having a great time with Aunt Phoebe.
瑞秋阿姨没什么用
Aunt Rachel hasn't been helpful at all.
你想我吗
So do you miss me?
有点  但我玩得太高兴了
Kind of, but I've just been having way too much fun.
你还没想家
Oh, so you're not homesick yet?
没有  应该没有
No, I don't think so.
我们七个都很想你
All right, well, the seven of us miss you.
哪七个  我  瑞秋
Who's seven? Well, you know, me, Rachel...
鸡  鸭  3个宝宝
...the birds, the babies.
宝宝也想我
Aw, the babies miss me?
彼萨来了  你们趁我不在叫彼萨
Ooh, pizza guy's here. What? You ordered pizza without me?
对  但我们想着你  所以特地点了乔伊特餐
Yeah, but we were thinking about you. We ordered the Joey Special.
两个披萨
Two pizzas?
对  我得挂了  再聊  等等  你们叫哪家的
Yeah. Okay, gotta go. Talk to you later. Wait, wait. Where did you get it from?
Where everybody knows your name
(欢乐酒店)
And they're always glad you came
You wanna be where you can see The troubles are all the same
You wanna be Where everybody knows your name
摩妮卡  你带我来这里干什么  等着瞧
Monica, why have you brought me here of all places?! You'll see.
我跟你讲  我们不会结婚了
I tell you, this wedding is not gonna happen.
罗斯
Oh, Ross.
好  想像一下更多的灯火  少一点砖瓦
Okay? But imagine a lot more lights, okay, and, you know, fewer bricks...
还有鲜花蜡烛
...and flowers and candles.
乐队可以摆在这里
Okay, and the musicians, they can go over here, okay?
椅子可以朝这边   然后…
And the chairs, they can face this way and...
你讲
You go.
不过要是你不喜欢  我们就改地点
But if you don't love this, then we'll do it any other place...
改时间
...any other time.
真的  没关系  你高兴就好
Really, it's fine. Whatever you want.
这样很完美
It's perfect.
我不知道  要是下雨   那就淋湿吧
And, I don't know, if it starts to rain... Well, then we'll get wet.
我连男朋友都没有
I don't even have a date.
菲比  什么
Pheebs? Yeah?
你记得饲料在哪里吗
Do you remember where the duck food is?
记得  在男生那边的水槽下面  怎么了
Yeah, it's in the guys' apartment, under the sink. Why?
因为我要去伦敦
Because I'm going to London.
什么  什么叫你要去伦敦
What? What do you mean, you're going to London?
我得告诉罗斯我爱他
Yeah, I have to tell Ross that I love him.
保重  等我回来再生
Now, honey, you take care, and you don't have those babies till I get back. Mwah.
你不能去  罗斯爱的是艾蜜莉
Rachel, you can't go. Ross loves Emily.
我知道  我知道  但我得告诉他我的感觉
I know, I know, I know he does, but I have to tell him how I feel.
他应该知道所有的状况  好做出决定
He deserves to have all of the information. Then he can make an informed decision.
不会吧  你去是希望他说
That's not why you're going. You're going because you hope he'll say:
"我也爱你  忘掉那个英国妹了"
"Yeah, I love you too, Rach. Forget about that British chippie."
你觉得他会吗
Do you think he will?
不会   因为他爱那个英国妹
No, because he's in love with the British chippie.
你去了只会把他搞乱  毁了他的婚礼
Look, Rachel, if you go, you're just gonna mess with his head and ruin his wedding.
太迟了  你错过机会了
You know? It's too late. You missed your chance.
抱歉  我知道你一定很难受
I'm sorry. I know this must be really hard.
但已经结束了
But it's over.
不  有人说 "我愿意" 才算结束
You know what? No. It's not over until someone says "I do."
我愿意  我愿意  我愿意
I do. I do! I do!
反正我也追不上你  谁让我怀了一窝宝贝呢
Yeah, like I can really chase you. I'm carrying a litter.